Guide to the Kennell A. Jackson Collection on Branner Hall
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kennell A. Jackson collection on Branner Hall
1960-2004
SC0789
Jackson, Kennell A., 1941-2005.
3.75 Linear feet (7 boxes)
These materials were collected by Kennell A. Jackson during his tenure as Resident Fellow in Branner Hall at Stanford. Included are Branner yearbooks, directories, and assorted newsletters; scripts from Branner orientation skits, 1991-2003, and other plays put on by dorm residents; dorm guides, brochures, rules, etc.; Jackson's communications to Resident Assistants and the dorm in general and letters he received from residents and former residents, 1983-2004; flyers from Branner Presents and other dorm events; a photograph album from the 1974-1975 year and other loose photographs; and reports by dormitory staff, 1987-1999.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given to the Stanford University Archives by the estate of Kennell A. Jackson in 2005.
Information about Access
Materials in box 7 are restricted. The collection is otherwise open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Kennell A. Jackson, who joined the Stanford faculty as professor of African history in 1969, was the Resident Fellow in Branner Hall (an all-freshman dormitory) from 1980 until his death in 2005.
Description of the Collection
These materials were collected by Kennell A. Jackson during his tenure as Resident Fellow in Branner Hall at Stanford. Included are Branner yearbooks, directories, and assorted newsletters; scripts from Branner orientation skits, 1991-2003, and other plays put on by dorm residents; dorm guides, brochures, rules, etc.; Jackson's communications to Resident Assistants and the dorm in general and letters he received from residents and former residents, 1983-2004; flyers from Branner Presents and other dorm events; a photograph album from the 1974-1975 year and other loose photographs; and reports by dormitory staff, 1987-1999. Other items of note are materials on the design and construction of the Branner puppet head and items pertaining to the theft of a "Grimace" statue from a local McDonald's, 1987.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Branner Hall.; College students--California.; Dormitory life--California--Stanford
Collection Contents
- Branner yearbooks 1977-1978, 1983-1992, and "Absolut Branner" undated (Box 1)
- Branner yearbooks, 1996-2000 (Box 2)
- Branner directories, 2000-2001, 2004-2005 (Box 2)
- Branner Banner Vol. 2, No. 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Branner Events, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Branner guides, brochures, staff lists, etc., 1960-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Branner Manor completed survey forms, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Branner musical scripts, 1985-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Branner newsletter, 1996 and undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Branner orientation skit, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Branner orientation skit, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Branner orientation skit, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Branner orientation skit, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Branner orientation skit, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Branner orientation skit, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Branner orientation skit, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Branner orientation skit, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Branner orientation skits, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Branner pages from Face Book, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Branner Presents (speakers series), 1980-91 and undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Branner puppet head (materials re its design and construction) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Branner Quarterly Vol. 1 and 2, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Branner RA master list, 1982-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Branner RA promo book, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Branner RAs, images, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Branner renovation, 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, general, 1983-2005, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Dorm elections (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Dorm floor plans and assigned rooms (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Flyers for Branner events (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Guides, rules, etc. for staff, 1997-2003, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Hall meeting agendas, 1988-2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Kennell - items about (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Kennell - letters to RAs and general dorm, 1984-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Kennell's cookies - notices and one recipe (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Kennell's outlines and text for talks re Stanford, dorm life, etc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Korobkin, Russell, report as academic coordinator, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Letters to Kennell from Branner residents and former residents, 1983-2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- McDonald's Grimace event, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Orientation evaluation results, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Photographs (Box 4, Folder 4)
- RA reflections, notes, 1987, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Soto dictionary, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- U.S. News and World Report, college ranking issues, 1996-2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Wang, Bruce, report as advising associate, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Wulfstat, Matt, "Branner Sucks?" (class paper?), 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Branner's Interactive Multimedia Magazine, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Assorted flyers for Branner events (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Photo album, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Framed letter from Milton Friedman after talk at Branner, with Rose Friedman's chocolate chip cookie recipe, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Framed photograph of a group of Branner students (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Framed photograph "The Branner Leg from Rapp's Shoe Store" (Box 6, Folder 3)
- RA applications [restricted] (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Staff applications [restricted] (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Confidential matters [restricted] (Box 7, Folder 3)